Guide to the William Heyen Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- May 2006 Acquisition, circa 1950-2006; 2; (13 boxes)
  - Writings, 1990s-2005
    - Misc poetry, loose unsorted items, manuscripts (Box 26)
    - Misc poems [for "To William Merwin"?], manuscripts, 2 (Box 26)
    - Poems for "To William Merwin," manuscript volume (Box 26)
    - "To William Merwin in his Eightieth Year," typescript (in chronological order), 2004 Jan-Dec; 30 (Box 26)
    - Misc. poems for "the Orphanage," manuscript volume (Box 26)
    - "The Orphanage," typescripts, 2005 Mar; 2 (Box 26)
    - "The Angel Voices," manuscript (Box 26)
    - Misc. from "The Angel Voices," manuscript (Box 26)
    - "The Angel Voices," typescripts, 1998 Aug-2005 Feb; 6 (Box 26)
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts and loose inserts in notebooks, 3 (Box 27)
    - "The Exact Location of the Soul," typescript (Box 27)
    - "The Rope / Tumbleweed / Waterhook," typescript (Box 27)
    - "Annuli," manuscripts and typescripts (Box 28)
    - "Annuli," printed copy (Box 28)
    - Misc. poems, manuscripts, 2 (Box 28)
    - "Four Songs," manuscript (Box 28)
    - "Perpetrator" and "Child," manuscript (Box 28)
    - Misc. poems, including "The Confessions: Ten on Williams" and "W.C. Williams poems," manuscript and typescript (Box 28)
    - "Iwo Dahlia," manuscripts and typescripts (Box 28)
    - Di Gennaro, Adrian,"Acts of Contrition," typescript (Box 28)
    - "Menagerie," manuscripts and typescripts with print copy (Box 28)
    - "Coral," manuscript (Box 28)
    - "The Rope," typescript (Box 28)
    - Misc. Correspondence with Mammoth Books (Box 28)
    - Miscellaneous, manuscripts (Box 28)
    - "Brockport Milkweed," typescript (Box 28)
    - "The Hummingbird Corporation," typescripts, 2 (Box 28)
    - Misc. Correspondence with Katrina Roberts (Box 28)
    - Miscellaneous "New Pig Notes for Mafia Joy," manuscripts and typescripts (Box 28)
    - "Cauldron," manuscript (Box 28)
    - Misc. Correspondence with Watson, David et. al., "Watson Lowery Interview" (Box 28)
    - Miscellaneous, typescripts (Box 28)
    - Misc. Correspondence (Box 28)
    - "Fana Al-Fana," manuscript and typescripts (Box 28)
    - Miscellaneous, manuscripts and typescripts, 3 (Box 28)
    - Misc. Printed Material (Box 28)
    - "George Bellows: Autumn Brook (1922)" Printed Broadsides, signed
    - Giancola, Dan, "Songs from the Army of the Working Stiffs," Printed copy (Box 28)
    - Heyen, William, "Brockport Sunflowers" Printed copy (Box 28)
    - Heyen, William, "Depth of Field," printed copy (Box 28)
    - Heyen, William, "The Hummingbird Corporation," printed copies, 2 (Box 28)
    - Heyen, William, "Menagerie," printed copy (Box 28)
    - National Book Foundation,"The 55th National Book Awards," printed copy (Box 28)
    - Heyen, William, Misc. notebook, manuscripts (Box 28)
    - Heyen, William, misc. correspondence and manuscripts of poems (Box 29)
    - Heyen, William, "Rhymed Poems for Grant Holcomb," typescript (Box 29)
    - Heyen, William, "The Novelist," typescript (Box 29)
    - Swann, Brian, "Snow House," typescript (Box 29)
    - Jellema, Rod, "Slender Grace," typescript (Box 29)
    - Kramer, Aaron, "Wicked Times," typescript (Box 29)
    - Davis, Todd, "Prairie Liturgy," typescript (Box 29)
    - Hill, Laban Carrick, "Air Start," typescript (Box 29)
    - Hellus, Al, Miscellaneous, typescript, and correspondence with Heyen (Box 29)
    - Bourne, Daniel, "Where No One Spoke the Language," typescript (Box 29)
    - Esposito, Duane, "Cadillac Battleship," typescript (Box 29)
  - Oversize
    - "George Bellows: Autumn Brook (1922)" Printed Broadsides, signed (from Writings) (Box 30)
    - Heyen, Hannelore, political campaign poster "Hanny Heyen for Village Trustee" (from Correspondence) (Box 30)
- August 2006 Acquisition, 1984-2005; 3; (1 box)
  Formerly classed as Uncat MSS 887.
  - Channel, by Barbara Jordan, typescript, inscribed to William Heyen (Box 31)
  - Reptilian sheen, chapbook (Box 31)
  - Snare, Vol. 1, issues 1-2 and Vol. 2, issue 1 (Box 31)
  - 2 TLS to William Heyen, I TLS to Christopher Ricks, and 1 TLS to Robert Pinsky with typescript poem, from Barbara Jordan. (Box 31)
- January 2010 Acquisition, 1961-2009; 4; (13 boxes)
  Arranged into four series: Correspondence, Writings, Journals, and Collaboration with Robert E. Marx.
  - Correspondence, 1961; 1971-2009
    Arranged into two series: Alphabetical and Chronological.
    - Alphabetical, 1988-2009
      - A, 2006-2007 (Box 32)
        Alubiadi, Maan
        Aizenberg, Susan
        Axelrod, David
      - Andai, Ferenc, 2008 Feb-Aug (Box 32)
      - Bowling, Tim, 2006-2009 (Box 32)
      - B, 2006-2009 (Box 32)
        Bentley, Roy
        Berry, Wendell
        Bizarro, Patrick
        Black, Ralph
        Blockeel, Dirk
        Borenstein, Emily
        Bourne, Daniel
        Brady, Phil
        Broomfield, Michael
      - Cotter, Craig, 2008-2009 (Box 32)
      - C, 2008-2009 (Box 32)
        Clemente, Vince
        Cohen, William
        Cologne-Brooks
        Conlon, Christopher
        Cotter, Craig
        Culver, Bonnie
      - D, 1999-2009 (Box 32)
        Davis, Todd
        Dissette, James
        Docking, Mike
        Dove, Rita
        Dunn, Stephen
        Duva, Gregory
      - Esposito, Duane, 2007 Jun-Aug (Box 32)
      - F, 2003-2009 (Box 32)
        Fishman, Charles
        Fitzpatrick, Richard
        Forester, Richard
        Frisella, Pat
      - Giancola, Don, 1999-2009 (Box 32)
      - H, 1993-2009 (Box 32)
        Hall, Donald
        Haven, Stephen
        Hazo, Sam
        Hellus, Al
        Hix, Harvey L.
        Hix, Joshua
        Holcomb, Grant
      - Jordan, Barbara, 2009 Apr 27 (Box 32)
      - K, 1988-2009 (Box 32)
        Katz, Eliot
        Keil, John M.
        Kinnell, Galway
        Kramer, Aaron
        Krapf, Norbert
      - L, 1995-2008 (Box 32)
        Ladin, Jay
        Lee, Li-Young
        Longenbach, James
        Lykling, Mick
      - Merwin. Willian S., 2006-2008 (Box 32)
      - M, 2005-2009 (Box 32)
        Mariani, Paul
        Masterson, Dan
        Matthews, Jack
        Memmer, Phil
        Metres, Philip
        Minty, Judith
        Mooney, Robert
        Morgan, Robert
        Mullen, James
      - McKee, Louis, 2006-2007 (Box 32)
      - O, 2002-2009 (Box 32)
        Oates-Smith, Joyce Carol
        Ozick, Cynthia
      - P, 1989-2009 (Box 32)
        Plumly, Stanley
        Phillips, Robert
        Poniewaz, Jeff
        Prager, June
      - R, 2007-2008 (Box 32)
        Rizzuto, Helen, M.
      - S, 1989-2009 (Box 32)
        Stafford, Kim
        Spires, Elizabeth
        Stryk, Daniel and Suzanne
        Swann, Brian
        Snodgrass, W. D.
        Siegel, Robert
        Schraffenberger, Jeremy
      - Silko, Leslie Marmon, 2008 Jan-Jun (Box 32)
      - T, 2008-2009 (Box 32)
        Terman, Philip
        Tillett, R.
      - Vallone, Antonio, 2006-2008 (Box 32)
      - W, 1993-2008 (Box 32)
        Waters, Michael
        Watson, David
        Wright, Charles
      - Zimmer, Paul, 2006-2009 (Box 32)
    - Chronological, 1961;1971-2009
      - Letters of Praise, 1971-1981 (Box 32)
      - SUNY Brockport basketball photo, 1961
      - 1977 1977 (Box 32)
      - 1981 1981 (Box 32)
      - 1982 1982 (Box 32)
      - 1984 1984 (Box 32)
      - 1985 1985 (Box 32)
      - 1988 1988 (Box 32)
      - 1989 1989 (Box 32)
      - 1996 1996 (Box 32)
      - 1998 1998 (Box 32)
      - 2001 2001 (Box 32)
      - 2002 2002 (Box 32)
      - 2003 2003 (Box 32)
      - 2004 2004 (Box 32)
      - 2005 2005 (Box 32)
      - 2006 2006, 4 (Box 32)
      - 2006 2006, 2 (Box 33)
      - 2007 2007, 4 (Box 33)
      - 2008 2008, 5 (Box 33)
      - 2009 2009, 2 (Box 33)
      - undated undated (Box 33)
  - Writings, 2005-2009
    Arranged into three subseries: Drafts, Galley Proofs, and Annotated Books.
    - Drafts, 2005-2009
      - "Barnes" notebook, circa 2008-2009 (Box 34)
        Note by Heyen on inside flyleaf reads: "This notebook contains drafts of many Holocaust poems including 'Art' & 'The Maggots Speak' & 'Religion,' [these three poems to appear in American Poetry Review], many of The Orphanage poemlets, many sections of the Straight Suite for Frank O'Hara, and of many miscallaneous poems."
      - Red Notebook, circa 2005-2006 (Box 34)
        Note by Heyen on inside flyleaf reads: "This notebook contains drafts of dozens of the poems for The Football Corporations; also of 'Skunk Years,' 'After Sept. 11: Wall Street,' 'Shoah Goat,' 'Dr. Heim,' 'Sunlight,' 'Two Young Men,' 'The Devil's Ballad;' also the drafts of a few new 'pig notes.'" Several of these poems appeared in A Poetics of Hiroshima. Also included are drafts of "Museum Visitor Coda" and "To William Merwin."
      - Black notebook, circa 2007-2008 (Box 34)
        Note by Heyen on inside flyleaf reads: "This notebook contains drafts of the pignote 'Art,' the bookstore poem, some poems toward The Football Corporations, 'From the Fields,' 'Family Dream,' hundreds of poems toward The Orphanage, 'Classmate,' 'Cage,' drafts of Village Board pieces including the one on the letter that was not a letter published locally, the suite of Yankee poems, 'Pitch' & 'Speak, Memory' that went into A Poetics of Hiroshima, the pig note 'Oxymoron,' and much more."
      - The Angel Voices, circa 2007; 2 (Box 34)
      - A Poetics of Hiroshima, circa 2007-2008; 4 (Box 34)
      - A Poetics of Hiroshima and the Angel Voices, circa 2007-2009; 3 (Box 34)
      - The Football Corporations, circa 2006; 2 (Box 34)
      - The Orphanage: 650 poems, circa 2006 (Box 34)
      - The Orphanage: 700 poems, circa 2006 (Box 34)
      - Crazy Horse and the Custers: the River of Electricity, circa 2006 (Box 34)
      - Blueberries Album, circa 2007 (Box 34)
      - To William Merwin, circa 2007 (Box 34)
      - Greatest Hits Pudding House, circa 2006 (Box 34)
      - loose manuscripts, circa 2005-2007; 11 (Box 34)
    - Galley Proofs
      - Long Island Light (Box 35)
      - Noise in the Trees, 3 (Box 35)
      - Swastika Poems, 2 (Box 35)
    - Annotated Books
      - Anissimov, Myriam. Primo Levi: Tragedy of an Optimist (Box 36)
        This book's back flyleaf contains the first draft of part of Section XIV of To William Merwin: A Poem (2007).
      - Bauman, Janina. Winter in the Morning: A Young Girl's Life in the Warsaw Ghetto and Beyond 1939–1945 (Box 36)
        This book contains the first drafts of the poem "Evidence," which appears in Shoah Train.
      - Brown, David E. Aldo Leopold's Wilderness (Box 36)
        This book contains the first drafts of a few of the poems that went into Crazy Horse in Stillness (1996).
      - Browning, Frank. The Vanishing Land: Corporate Theft of America's Soil (Box 36)
        This book holds the 1st draft of section 27 of The Chestnut Rain (1986).
      - Carse, James P. Breakfast at the Victory: The Mysticism of Ordinary Experience (Box 36)
        This book contains the 1st draft of "Sycamore," which appears in Pig Notes and Dumb Music (1998), and the draft of another piece that I might look at again. Also contains the first draft of "Fana Al-Fana" which William B. Ewert published as a broadside and which later appeared in The Confessions of Doc Williams and Other Poems (2006).
      - Christianson, Gale E. Fox at the Wood's Edge: A Biography of Loren Eiseley (Box 36)
        This book contains the first drafts of a poem called "Coils" that appeared in Crazy Horse in Stillness (1996).
      - Clark, Tom. Charles Olson: The Allegory of a Poet's Life (Box 36)
        On p. 266 is the first draft of a poem which appeared in Redactions.
      - Czarnecki, Joseph. Last Traces: The Lost Art of Auschwitz (Box 36)
        Contains first drafts of "A Kite" (abandoned) and "The Bear" (included in Shoah Train ).
      - Davis, Millrd C. The Near Woods (Box 36)
        Contains drafts of certain sections of The Chestnut Rain.
      - Dawidowicz, Lucy S. From that Place and Time: A Memoir 1938-1947 (Box 36)
        Contains the first drafts of lthe poem "Candy" which appears in Shoah Train.
      - Delbo, Charlotte. Auschwitz and After (Box 37)
        This book contains the first draft of the poem that became "Blanket" which appears in Shoah Train. Also contains other drafts.
      - Dodge, Tom. A Literature of Sports (Box 37)
        This book's back flyleaves contain drafts of an unfinished poem. Heyen adopted this text for his Literature of Sport class and laid in various course sheets, including a syllabus.
      - Dwork, Deborah and van Pelt, Robert Jan. Auschwitz: 1270 to the Present (Box 37)
        This book contains the first drafts of "Roof" and "Shoah Train" appearing in Shoah Train. "Roof" also appeared in Kenyon Review.
      - Engelberg, Morris and Schneider, Marv. DiMaggio: Setting the Record Straight (Box 37)
        This book contains the first drafts of "Heaven," which appeared in the July-August 2009 issue of Atlantic, "Elegy," and several poems for The Orphanage.
      - Erdstein, Erich. Inside the Fourth Reich (Box 37)
        Contains the first draft of "The Trains," which appeared in Erika: Poems of the Holocaust (1984).
      - Feinstein, Elaine. Ted Hughes: The Life of a Poet (Box 37)
        This book contains initial efforts toward stanzas of To William Merwin: A Poem (2007).
      - Fischer, Klaus P. The History of an Obsession: German Judeophobia and the Holocaust (Box 37)
        This book contains first drafts of the poems "Euthanasia Economy" and "Ocean" which appear in Shoah Train.
      - Fowles, John and Horvat, Frank. The Tree (Box 37)
        On p. 42 is the first draft of "The Mystical" from Crazy Horse in Stillness.
      - Freiwald, Aaron. The Last Nazi: Josef Schwammberger and the Nazi Past (Box 37)
        This book contains the first drafts of poems that appear in Shoah Train, including "Reprieve, 1939," "Art: Arnold Susskind," "The Eighth Station: Testimony of Sam Nussbaum," and "Pleurisy."
      - Furlong, Monica. Zen Effects: The Life of Alan Watts (Box 37)
        On p. 217 are drafts of an untitled poem.
      - Fussell, Paul. Poetic Meter and Poetic Form (Box 37)
        The back flyleaf of this book contains a draft of an untitled poem.
      - Gonnaud, Maurice. An Uneasy Solitude: Individual and Society in the Work of Ralph Waldo Emerson (Box 37)
        This book contains the first drafts of three poems that are part of the manuscript of Crazy Horse and the Custers: The River of Electricity. Also contains the first draft of a prose piece called "Character."
      - Graber, Kay, ed. Sister to the Sioux: the Memoirs of Elaine Goodale Eastman (Box 37)
        This book contains the first drafts of poems which appear in the Crazy Horse and the Custers manuscripts.
      - Greenspan, Henry. On Listening to Holocaust Survivors: Recounting and Life History (Box 37)
        Contains a poem titled, "Dachau Tourists."
      - Gribbin, John. Hothouse Earth: The Greenhouse Effect and Gaia (Box 38)
        This book contains a draft of "Varves" on p. 55 and back flyleaf.
      - Harris, Robert. Selling Hitler (Box 38)
        The back flyleaf of this volume contains the first draft of Heyen's poem that became "ID," included in Shoah Train.
      - Hatley, James. Suffering Witness (Box 38)
        Contains stanzas (pp. 9-10) of an untitled poem and an inlaid letter from James Hatley.
      - Herrigel, Eugen. Zen in the Art of Archery (Box 38)
        This book contains a draft of a "classroom poem" on back flyleaf, which Heyen calls, "Zen exercise," and an inlaid sheet of manuscript.
      - Jackson, Phil. Sacred Hoops. (Box 38)
        Page 58 of this book contains the first draft of a poem titled "Basketball Coach."
      - Jones, Richard. Ed. Poetry and Politics (Box 38)
        This book contains an unfinished poem on page 137. A course syllabus for a 1985 poetry workshop has been laid in.
      - Karst, Georg M. The Beasts of the Earth (Box 38)
        This book contains the first draft of the second section of "Three Relations," which appeared in Erika.
      - Keeble, John. Out of the Channel: The Exxon Valdez Oil Spill in Prince William Sound (Box 38)
        This book contains drafts of sections of what became "Losing Season," a poem which appeared in Cincinnati Review and was then abbreviated for The Rope (2003). The back inside cover also contains a poem titled, "The Device."
      - Klemperer, Victor. I Will Bear Witness, (2 volumes) (Box 38)
        Volume I contains "Jewish Doctors, Berlin Story, 1938" and "Mutilation, 1934," both of which appear in Shoah Train: Poems. The untitled poem on pp. 146-147 remains unpublished. Volume II contains, among others, drafts of "Decrees," "Track," "Star Song," and "Schnapps," all of which appear in Shoah Train.
      - Langer, Lawrence. Admitting the Holocaust: Collected Essays (Box 38)
        This book contains the first drafts of "Sound from Inside the Gas Chambers" and an early version of "Prayer" which is the first poem in Shoah Train.
      - Levi, Primo. Auschwitz Report (Box 38)
        This book contains first drafts of "Illumination Graft," which appeared in A Poetics of Hiroshima (2008), and an untitled poem.
      - Levi, Primo. The Drowned and the Saved (Box 38)
        This book contains a first draft of "Parity," which appears in Shoah Train.
      - Levi, Primo. The Sixth Day and Other Tales (Box 38)
        This book contains untitled poem fragments.
      - Levi, Primo. Other People's Trades (Box 38)
        This book contains fragments of an unpublished essay.
      - Levi, Primo. Conversations (Box 38)
        The draft of an unfinished poem is visible on page 31.
      - Longenbach, James. Wallace Stevens: The Plain Sense of Things (Box 39)
        This book contains the first drafts of several poems including "Nesconset, AM," which appears in The Confessions of Doc Williams (2006).
      - MacLeish, William H. The Day Before America: Changing the Nature of a Continent (Box 39)
        This book contains the first drafts of poems that appeared in Crazy Horse in Stillness (1996). Two letters (dated 1989 and 1996), from William MacLeish to William Heyen, are laid in between the front cover and flyleaf.
      - Malcolm, Norman. Ludwig Wittgenstein: A Memoir. (Box 39)
        This book holds the 1st draft of my poem "Wittgenstein," which appeared in The City Parables (1980).
      - Mariani, Paul. William Carlos Williams: A New World Naked (Box 39)
        This book contains a few first drafts of poems appearing in The Confessions of Doc Williams.
      - Matthiessen, Peter. Nine-Headed Dragon River: Zen Journals (Box 39)
        An untitled poem appears on page 140.
      - McKibben, Bill. Hope, Human and Wild (Box 39)
        Contains the first draft (p.7) of a yet unpublished poem, and the first draft of the poem that became "Subway" and appears in The Rope (2003).
      - McPhee, John. Rising from the Plains (Box 39)
        This book contains the first drafts of two poems that appeared in Crazy Horse in Stillness (1996) and a 3 x 5 card laid in with a draft of another poem.
      - Melchior, Ib and Brandenburg, Frank. Quest: Searching for Germany's Nazi Past. (Box 39)
        This book contains the first drafts of "Swans" and "Bloodhound" which appear in Shoah Train.
      - Messegue, Maurice. Of Men and Plants (Box 39)
        This book contains the first draft of section XLVIII of Noise in the Trees (1974).
      - Mitchell, John Hanson. Living at the End of Time. (Box 39)
        This book contains the first draft of the poem that became "Walden" which appears in The Rope (2003).
      - Nero, Robert W. Redwings (Box 39)
        This book contains the 1st draft of "Epaulettes" which appeared in Crazy Horse in Stillness.
      - Newcomb, Richard F. Iwo Jima (Box 39)
        This book contains the first drafts of many stanzas of "Iwo Dahlia," a poem appearing in A Poetics of Hiroshima & Other Poems.
      - Niewyk, Donald L. Fresh Wounds: Early Narratives of Holocaust Survival (Box 39)
        This book contains the first drafts of several poems appearing in Shoah Train.
      - Noel, Daniel. Seeing Castaneda (Box 39)
        This book contains, among drafts of other poems, the first draft of "Castaneda," which appears in Pig Notes & Dumb Music (1998).
      - Norton, M.D. Herter. Translations from the Poetry of Rainer Maria Rilke (Box 39)
        This book contains the first draft of "Lament" that appears in Erika: Poems of the Holocaust.
      - Nyiszli, Miklos. Auschwitz: A Doctor's Eyewitness Account (Box 40)
        This book contains early drafts of several poems that appear in Shoah Train, including "Bread," "Auschwitz Reich Disfigured Haiku Sequence," "Luftpost," "The Pines," "Stones: the Efficacy of Poetry," "Ardor," and "Had."
      - Poller, Walter. Medical Block Buchenwald (Box 40)
        This book contains the first drafts of the poem that became "Communion Spoon" to be included in Shoah Train.
      - Rabinowitz, Dorothy. New Lives: Survivors of the Holocaust Living in America (Box 40)
        This book contains the first draft of "The Hair: Jacob Korman's Story" which appeared in Erika.
      - Rees, Laurence. Auschwitz: A New History (Box 40)
        This book contains first drafts of "The Word," "The Carriages," "Exercise," "The Poet Laureate Speaks," "Poetry."
      - Rosenberg, David. Ed. Testimony: Contemporary Writers Make the Holocaust Personal. (Box 40)
        This book contains the first drafts of the poem that became "The Others," which appears in Shoah Train.
      - Sakutaro, Hagiwara. Face at the Bottom of the World (Box 40)
        This book contains drafts of the unpublished poem "Slug."
      - Sandoz, Mari. The Buffalo Hunters (Box 40)
        This book contains the first drafts of several poems that appeared in Crazy Horse in Stillness (1996). "Aerial View, BC," "Ice," "Providence," "Friendlies," and "Libido Saloon."
      - Schloegl, Irmgard. The Wisdom of the Zen Masters (Box 40)
        The back flyleaf contains the 1st draft of a prose piece that appears in Pig Notes & Dumb Music: Prose on Poetry.
      - Schumach, Murray. The Diamond People (Box 40)
        This book contains the first drafts of a couple pieces in Pig Notes & Dumb Music: Prose on Poetry (1998).
      - Selzer, Richard. Mortal Lessons: Notes on the Art of Surgery (Box 40)
        First drafts of "The Dome" are written on back flyleaves. "The Dome" appears in The Confessions of Doc Williams & Other Poems (2006).
      - Shapard, Robert and James Thomas. Sudden Fiction: American Short-Short Stories (Box 40)
        First drafts of "The Village," "Son" and "Grist" are in this book. These stories appear in The Hummingbird Corporation: Stories (2003).
      - Sipper, Ralph. Modern First Editions, Cat. 54. (Box 40)
        The last page here contains the first draft of my "Old Flame" that appears in The Hummingbird Corporation: Stories (2003).
      - Stafford, Kim. Early Morning: Remembering My Father (Box 40)
        This book contains poem fragements and an inlaid draft of a poem titled "Beginning with a line from William Stafford."
      - Steinberg, Paul. Speak You Also: A Survivor's Reckoning (Box 40)
        This book contains drafts of a couple poems including "Cabbage Steam."
      - Stevens, John. One Robe, One Bowl: The Zen Poetry of Ryokan. (Box 40)
        Note by Heyen reads: "The poem on the back fly leaf became a Tamarack postcard." The book also contains inlaid notes.
      - Stryk, Lucien. Encounter with Zen (Box 40)
        Contains drafts of a poem on the back flyleaf. This book is inscribed by Stryk for Han and Bill Heyen on the title page
      - Suzuki, Daisetz Teitaro. The Training of the Zen Buddhist Monk (Box 40)
        Poem fragments are scattered throughout.
      - Tall, Deborah. From Where We Stand: Recovering a Sense of Place (Box 40)